Finding aid to the Eleanor Louisa Lord papers CA.MS.01136
Smith College Archives
Eleanor Louisa Lord papers
1887-1956
Smith College Archives
Lord, Eleanor Louisa
CA.MS.01136
0.438 linear feet (1 container)
Eleanor Louisa Lord graduated from Smith College in 1887 and returned to teach History at Smith from 1890 to 1894. She returned to Smith again in 1922 to become an educational consultant, and in 1925 she became research associate to the institute of Coordination of Women's Interests at Smith. Her papers contain a memorabilia book and a bible book, documenting her student experience, as well as publications, news clippings, a travel log, postcards, and photographs documenting her professional life at Smith.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown.
Biographical / Historical
Eleanor Louisa Lord, Class of 1887, received her M.A. from Bryn Mawr in 1890 and her Ph.D. at Teachers college, Columbia and at Newnham College, University of Cambridge in 1896. She taught History at Smith College (1890-1894) and at Goucher College (1897-1919) where she became dean in 1910. In 1919, Lord became warden of Rockefeller Hall in Bryn Mawr, and left the position in 1922 to become a History professor at Wells. She returned to Smith in 1922 to become an educational consultant, and in 1925 she became research associate to the institute of Coordination of Women's Interests at Smith. She died in 1956 in Northampton.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains one memorabilia book and a bible from Eleanor Louisa Lord's time as a Smith student from 1883-1887. The book contains playbills, news clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, music programs, and photographs. The collection also contains Lord's professional papers, which include, obituaries, professional correspondence, American Association of University Women brochures, photographs, several publications about Smith alumnae, and postcards and a travel log from her trip to Europe in 1934.
Lord, Eleanor Louisa
- Instructor of History 1890-1894, Appointment Bureau Education Consultant 1922-1926, 1887-1891 (Box 931, Folder 1)
- General, 1956, undated (Box 931, Folder 2)
- Memorabilia, Bible book, 1887-1922 (Box 931, Folder 3)
- American Association of University Women, 1922-1940 (Box 931, Folder 4)
- AAUW Correspondence, 1912-1941 (Box 931, Folder 5)
- Travel Log, 1934 (Box 931, Folder 6)
- A Study of Smith College Graduates Engaged in Education Work, 1923-1925 (Box 931, Folder 7)
- Appointment Bureau Education Consultant, 1922-1923 (Box 931, Folder 8)
- Brochures, programs, 1934 (Box 931, Folder 9)
- Postcards, 1934 (Box 931, Folder 10)
- Photographs, undated (Box 931, Folder 11)
- Occupations and Interests, Smith Graduates, undated (Box 931, Folder 12)